<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE application [<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="general-api-information">
    <title>General API Information</title>
    <?dbhtml stop-chunking?>

    <para> Cloud Images brings access to the OpenStack Image Registry and Delivery Service directly to Rackspace open cloud
        customers, thereby providing services for discovering, registering, and retrieving virtual machine images and their
        metadata by using a RESTful API. </para>
    <para>Image <emphasis role="italics">sharing</emphasis> provides a mechanism for customers to give access to images in
        their account to other customers. Customer A initiates sharing with Customer B, and Customer B accepts the offer. The
        image is not copied into Customer B's repository, but Customer B has access to the image in Customer A's
        repository.</para>
    <para>Image <emphasis role="italics">import/export</emphasis> enables customers to import images into the Rackspace
        cloud. Customers upload the image to Cloud Files, and then they use the <emphasis role="italics">import</emphasis>
        feature to make it into a cloud image. They can store the cloud image in any Cloud Files location for future
        downloading.</para>
    <para>Cloud Images has the following expected benefits: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The open cloud becomes even more open.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Images are imported and exported among public cloud, private cloud and sources outside of
                    Rackspace.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are portable, taking full advantage of the open cloud.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are imported from a private cloud into the public cloud for cloud-bursting.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images created in the public cloud are imported to a private cloud, or to another provider's
                            cloud, for redundancy and high availability.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Customers share images.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Users with multiple accounts share images among the accounts.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are shared as an informal "image marketplace".</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <!--API Request and Response Information-->
    <section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="Reqresponse">
        <title>API Request and Response Information</title>
        <para>The Cloud Images API primarily accepts and serves <glossterm linkend="gl-json">JSON-encoded</glossterm> data.
            For uploading and downloading image files, the API also accepts and serves binary image data. Most requests that
            send JSON-encoded data must have the proper media type in their Content-Type header:
                <code>'application/json'</code>. HTTP &PATCH; requests must use the patch <glossterm linkend="gl-mediatype"
                >media type</glossterm> defined for the entity they intend to modify. Requests that upload image data should
            use the media type <code>'application/octet-stream'</code>.</para>
        <para>The necessary json-schema documents are provided at predictable <glossterm linkend="gl-uri">URIs</glossterm>. A
            consumer validates server responses and client requests based on the published schemas. The schemas contained in
            this document are only examples and should not be used to validate your requests. A client should always fetch
            schemas from the server.</para>
    </section>

    <!--Authentication-->
    <xi:include href="section_auth.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="section_identity_3roles.xml"/>
</chapter>
