<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="general-api-information">
    <title>General API Information</title>
    <para> Cloud Images brings access to the OpenStack Image Registry and Delivery Service directly to Rackspace open cloud
        customers, thereby providing services for discovering, registering, and retrieving virtual machine <glossterm
            baseform="image">images</glossterm> and their metadata by using a RESTful API. </para>
    <para>Image <emphasis role="italics">sharing</emphasis> provides a mechanism for customers to give access to images in
        their account to other customers. Customer A initiates sharing with Customer B, and Customer B accepts the offer. The
        image is not copied into Customer B's repository, but Customer B has access to the image in Customer A's
        repository.</para>
    <para>Image <emphasis role="italics">import/export</emphasis> enables customers to import images into the Rackspace
        cloud. Customers upload the image to Cloud Files, and then they use the <emphasis role="italics">import</emphasis>
        feature to make it into a cloud image. The export feature allows customers to copy images from Cloud Images into
        Cloud Files for future downloading.</para>
    <para>Cloud Images has the following expected benefits: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Images can be imported and exported among public cloud, private cloud and sources outside of
                    Rackspace.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are portable, taking full advantage of the open cloud.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are imported from a private cloud into the public cloud for cloud-bursting.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images created in the public cloud can be imported to a private cloud, or to another provider's
                            cloud, for redundancy and high availability.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Customers share images.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Users with multiple accounts share images among the accounts.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Images are shared as an informal "image marketplace".</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <!--API Request and Response Information-->
    <xi:include href="images-how-to-API.xml"/>

    <!--cURL Info-->
    <xi:include href="images-curl.xml"/>

    <!--Authentication-->
    <xi:include href="images-auth-main.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="images-identity-3roles.xml"/>
    
    <!--Export Env Vars-->
    <xi:include href="images-export-env-vars.xml"/>
</chapter>
