<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE application [<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;]>

<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="image-sharing">
    <title>Image sharing</title>
    <?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
    <para>Image producers create and share images with image consumers, allowing the consumers to use the shared image when
        booting a server. The producer shares an image with the consumer by making the consumer a <glossterm
            baseform="Image Member">member</glossterm> of that image. The consumer then accepts or rejects the image by
        changing the image member status. After it is accepted, the image appears in the consumer's image list. As long as
        the consumer is an member of the image, the consumer can use the image, regardless of the image member status.</para>
    <figure>
        <title>Sharing an image</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../figures/image-member.png" contentwidth="3in"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <note>
        <para>In the &CImA;, the image member status three purposes: <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The member status controls whether image appears in the consumer's image list. If the image member
                        status is <literal>accepted</literal>, the image appears in the consumer's image list. Otherwise, the
                        image does not appear in the image list.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The member status can be used to filter the consumer's image list. For example, the consumer can
                        discover images that have been shared with him or her by using the instructions in <phrase
                            condition="dev"><olink targetdoc="ci-devguide" targetptr="GET_listImages_images_Image_Calls"
                                >"GET_listImages_images_Image_Calls"</olink></phrase>
                        <phrase condition="gs"><olink targetdoc="ci-gettingstarted" targetptr="list-images">“List
                                images”</olink></phrase> and filtering the request by using
                            <code>visibility=shared&amp;member_status=pending</code>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The member status let's the producer know whether the consumer has seen and acted on the shared
                        image. If the status is <literal>accepted</literal> or <literal>rejected</literal>, the consumer has
                        definitely seen the shared image. If the status is <literal>pending</literal>, the consumer may not
                        have seen the request or may not have made a decision about it.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>For more information on image member status, see <olink condition="dev" targetdoc="ci-devguide"
                targetptr="member-statuses">“Image member statuses”</olink><olink condition="gs"
                targetdoc="ci-gettingstarted" targetptr="member-statuses">“Image member statuses”</olink>.</para>
    </note>
    <para> Image producers and consumers have different abilities and responsibilities regarding image sharing. The following
        list shows these abilities:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Image producers add or remove image members, but they may not modify the member status of an image
                    member. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Image producers and consumers view the status of image members. When listing image members, the
                    producers see all the image members, and the consumers see only themselves.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Image consumers change their own member status, but they may not add or remove themselves as an image
                    member. </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>Image consumers can boot from any image shared by the image producer, regardless of the member status,
                    as long as the consumer knows the image ID.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="sharing-flow">
        <title>Sample workflow for image sharing, after image creation</title>
        <!--<para>Following is a sample workflow for image sharing, after image creation:</para>-->
        <note>
            <para>Communications between the image producer and the consumer, like those described in this sample workflow,
                can include notifications, questions, and requests and must be arranged independent of the &CImA;, via email,
                phone, Twitter, or other channels.</para>
        </note>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The producer posts the availability of specific images.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A potential consumer provides the producer with the consumer's tenant ID. Optionally, the producer
                    might request the consumer's email address for notification purposes, but this is outside the scope of
                    the API.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The producer uses the &CImA; to share the image with the consumer.</para>
                <para><phrase condition="dev"><olink targetdoc="ci-devguide"
                            targetptr="POST_createImageMember_images__image_id__members_Image_Producer_Calls"
                            >"POST_createImageMember_images__image_id__members_Image_Producer_Calls"</olink> shows the API
                        method details.</phrase>
                    <phrase condition="gs"><olink targetdoc="ci-gettingstarted" targetptr="create-image-member">“Create an
                            image member”</olink> shows an example.</phrase></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Optionally, the producer notifies the consumer that the image has been shared and provides the image's
                    ID (<glossterm>UUID</glossterm>).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the consumer wants the image to appear in the image list, the consumer uses the &CImA; to change the
                    image member status to <literal>accepted</literal>.</para>
                <para><phrase condition="dev"><olink targetdoc="ci-devguide"
                            targetptr="PUT_updateImageMember_images__image_id__members__member_id__Image_Consumer_Calls"
                            >"PUT_updateImageMember_images__image_id__members__member_id__Image_Consumer_Calls"</olink> shows
                        the API method details.</phrase>
                    <phrase condition="gs"><olink targetdoc="ci-gettingstarted" targetptr="update-image-member">“Update an
                            image member”</olink> shows an example.</phrase></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the consumer subsequently wants to hide the image, the consumer uses the &CImA; to change the image
                    member status to <literal>rejected</literal>. If the consumer wants to hide the image, but is open to the
                    possibility of being reminded by the producer that the image is available, the consumer uses the &CImA;
                    to change the image member status to <literal>pending</literal>. </para>
                <para><phrase condition="dev"><olink targetdoc="ci-devguide"
                            targetptr="PUT_updateImageMember_images__image_id__members__member_id__Image_Consumer_Calls"
                            >"PUT_updateImageMember_images__image_id__members__member_id__Image_Consumer_Calls"</olink> shows
                        the API method details.</phrase>
                    <phrase condition="gs"><olink targetdoc="ci-gettingstarted" targetptr="update-image-member">“Update an
                            image member”</olink> shows an example.</phrase></para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
</section>
